<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Advertising &#8211; Martha Rotter</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/advertising/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another nerd</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 11:29:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144031741</site>	<item>
		<title>AUGH, My Eyes! My Eyes!</title>
		<link>/augh-my-eyes-my-eyes/</link>
				<comments>/augh-my-eyes-my-eyes/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 15:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[martha]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magazines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://martharotter.com/blog/index.php/2011/08/augh-my-eyes-my-eyes/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Having recently read both Des Traynor&#8217;s article on magazine versus print advertising and Andy Rutledge’s article on digital news being broken, I have a new problem.&#160; I notice I&#8217;m suddenly much more conscious of advertisements on websites and applications I use. This is a problem because I used to be so good at tuning out [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having recently read both <a title="On News and Advertising :: Contrast Blog" href="http://contrast.ie/blog/on-news-and-advertising/" target="_blank">Des Traynor&#8217;s article</a> on magazine versus print advertising and <a title="News Redux :: Andy Rutledge" href="http://andyrutledge.com/news-redux.php" target="_blank">Andy Rutledge’s article</a> on digital news being broken, I have a new problem.&nbsp; I notice I&#8217;m suddenly much more conscious of advertisements on websites and applications I use. </p>
<p><img style="background-image: none; border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin: 0px auto 6px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: block; float: none; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px" title="Hotmail - martharotter@hotmail.com - Windows Live-1" border="0" alt="Hotmail - martharotter@hotmail.com - Windows Live-1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Hotmail-martharotterhotmail.com-Windows-Live-11.jpg" width="84" height="240"></p>
<p>This is a problem because I used to be <em>so good</em> at tuning out the bouncing &#8220;HERE I AM LOOK AT ME LOOK AT ME&#8221; ads on the side of my browser.&nbsp; Today when I logged into an unnamed online account, I actually felt offended that this company decided it was okay for this obnoxious, attention-deprived ad to be in my face while I was trying to read and respond to email.&nbsp; I ended up sliding the browser over so the ad was off the page in order to actually concentrate on my email.</p>
<p>We shouldn&#8217;t have to do that.&nbsp; How effective can an advertisement be if people are so annoyed by it they move it out of view?&nbsp; </p>
<p>And furthermore, do ads like this actually work?&nbsp; The image on Des’ blog post indicates that for many categories, click-through rates are <strong>under .1%</strong>. I&#8217;d love to know what the click-through rate is for specifically those ads that bounce around screaming “CLICK ON THE DANCING MONKEY NOW FOR A FREE IPAD!” and &#8220;OMG YOU&#8217;RE THE 5,553,024,203 VISITOR AND YOU *WON*!!!!!!!!!!!&#8221;&nbsp; </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>GUESS WHAT? I LIKE ADS.</strong></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s something that may surprise some website owners: I <strong>like</strong> ads. I read ads, I forward ads to my friends that are entertaining, I re-watch ads when they&#8217;re clever or funny, and I can still sing many jingles of ads I heard as a kid on the radio or television.&nbsp; In fact, as someone who spends a lot of money buying magazines and print publications, there are even some I buy for the ads.&nbsp; Magazines like Bon Appétit and Elle have such gorgeous pictures that I rarely read the majority of the articles, I flip through images, and I never care if they&#8217;re ads or part of the magazine. I am not anti-advertisements.&nbsp; </p>
<p>Magazine creators, unlike website owners, are not surprised that their readers like their ads.&nbsp; They already knew this, and that’s why their ad prices can be so high for their printed publications.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>WHO IS MAKING MONEY FROM THESE ADS?</strong></p>
<p>What I don&#8217;t understand is if or how these ugly website ads actually work.&nbsp; Google AdSense must make some people money, because I know people who have gotten cheques from them.&nbsp; But they&#8217;ve never made any money from me clicking on things.&nbsp; </p>
<p>I&#8217;d love to see a website that curated its advertisements<img style="background-image: none; border-right-width: 0px; margin: 5px 5px 6px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; display: inline; float: right; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; border-left-width: 0px; padding-top: 0px" title="Atlantic Magazine Ad" border="0" alt="Atlantic Magazine Ad" align="right" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/photo-21.png" width="160" height="240"> as carefully as the print magazines I read do.&nbsp; If the advertisements online were as good as they are in print, I&#8217;d likely click or interact with them more.&nbsp; As an example, in the <a title="Tuesday Newsday :: The Atlantic Magazine" href="/tuesday-newsday-the-atlantic-magazine/" target="_blank">Atlantic app review I did last week</a>, the single ad was a very well done advertisement for the new 2012 Mercedes-Benz CLS. I played with the ad for a while &amp; spent some time with it because it was cool and nicely done.&nbsp; (I’m not currently car shopping, but I would have interacted with many ads which were as well-designed as this one.)</p>
<p>Is that unrealistic?&nbsp; Most websites probably don&#8217;t have the time or money to hand-select advertisements or to be picky about them or send them back when they&#8217;re ugly.&nbsp; Plus many websites and applications use advertisement placement services, like Google AdSense, AdMob and Microsoft pubCenter, which don&#8217;t give them any control at all other than possibly the dimensions and the placement on the site for the ads and the option to exclude competitors or certain URLs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>A BETTER WAY?</strong></p>
<p>What if there were another way?&nbsp; If you could use an ad placement service like AdSense and guarantee that the advertisements were of a certain quality bar or that they had been vetted by a graphic designer or someone with taste, wouldn&#8217;t you?</p>
<p>People complain all the time about the fact that there is less and less money to be made from online advertising. I think many people are wasting opportunities by creating obnoxious and tasteless ads that don&#8217;t do any justice to their product.</p>
<p>Starting today I&#8217;m going to run a small experiment.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to see how long I can go without looking at bad online advertisements. When I come across a site that uses ads which drive me crazy, I&#8217;m going to put it on my &#8220;blocked&#8221; list.&nbsp; By the end of next week I will either have long since abandoned the idea as impossible or have created a list of sites that I no longer need to visit.&nbsp; But also I am hoping to find some sites that are shining examples of how to use great ads online.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>/augh-my-eyes-my-eyes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
